Kenneth C.M. Sills: Administrative Records A01.02.08
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
- Subject Files, 1917-1954, undated, A01.02.08.03; 42185; 12 Linear Feet
  - Faculty Relation to July 1951 (1949-51), 42432 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Faculty - Teaching Opportunities, 42433 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Tenure 1950, 42434 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Finnish Relief Fund 1939-40, 42435 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Fire Prevention 1922-23, 42436 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - First National Bank 1940-41, 42437 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Flag - Display, Use, Etc. (C.F. Robinson 2/19/45), 42438 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Folsom Engineering Co. 1930-31, 42439 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Ford Foundation 1951-52, 42440 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fraternity Matters 1943-51, 42441 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fraternity Matters - Bars 1951, 42442 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - General Convention (Atlantic City) October 1934, 42443 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Geology Course, 42444 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Gibson, Harvey Dow '02 - Death and Tributes 1950-51, 42445 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gibson Music Hall 1952, 42446 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Glee Club Concert 1948, 42447 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Goat Incident 1947, 42448 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Goff, Robert F. 1925-26, 42449 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Golf - Petitions 1952, 42450 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Governing Boards of Bowdoin College 1921-1924, 42451 (Box 7, Folder 28-30)
  - Meeting of the Boards - Reports etc. 1924, 42452 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Governing Boards, Special Meeting 1924, 42453 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Governing Boards- Trustees of Overseers 1925, 42454 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Governing Boards, Special Meeting 1927, 42455 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Special Meeting of the Governing Boards February 7, 1942, 42456 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Governing Boards - Commencement May 1942, 42457 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Meeting of the Boards Special Meeting January 23, 1943, 42458 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Meeting of the Boards 1944-45, 42459 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Governing Boards Meetings April 15, 1944 and May 31,-June 2, 1945, 42460 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Votes Passed by Governing Boards June 1946, 42461 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Governing Boards - Recommendations of Visiting Committee and List of Governing Boards Members 1946-47, 42462 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Governing Boards Meetings (including Special Meetings) 1947-52, 42463 (Box 7, Folder 42-56)
  - Gray, A. Shirley Will 1944-46, 42464 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Guggenheim, John Simon Memorial Foundation 1940-49, 42465 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Haldane Cup 1945 (#267), 42466 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Harvard Conference December 14, 1951, 42467 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Foundation 1950-51, 42468 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Harvard Group (American Defense) 1941-44, 42469 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hawthorne Letters (Maurice - Athens, PA) 1949-50, 42470 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hawthorne Memorabilia 1934-37, 42471 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Holiday Greeting from President Sills, 1936, 1947, 1949-1951, 117233 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Honorarium Praesidis 1927, 42472 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees, Prizes and Awards, Phi Beta Kappa, 42473 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
  - Honoris Causa 1948-49, 42474 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hormell Cup n.d., 42475 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Huebner Foundation (Academic staff) 1943-48, 42476 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Howe Scholarship 1945, 42477 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Immigration, Bureau of 1927-46, 42478 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Inauguration, 1918, 42479 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Inauguration 1952, 42480 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Inauguration greetings, 1918, 42481 (Ovsz-box 1)
  - Institute, "Man and His Earth", 1941, 42482 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Institute of Modern History 1923, 42483 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Institute of Modern Literature (Longfellow- Hawthorne Centenary) 1925 (Folder 1/2), 42484 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Institute of Modern Literature (Longfellow- Hawthorne Centenary) 1925 (Folder 2/2), 42485 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Institute of Modern Literature, 1933 Apr, 42486 (Box 8, Folder 24a)
  - Insurance Committee, 42487 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - James Bowdoin Day 1941, 1945-51, 42488 (Box 8, Folder 26-33)
  - Kent Island Annual Reports 1936-42, 42489 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Kent Island Correspondence 1935-42, 42490 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Kent Island Student Evaluations 1938, 42491 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Kenyon College 1951-52, 42492 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Laws, Revision of 1923-24, 42493 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Letter about College from President Sills, 1933, 117234 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Library Committee, 42494 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Loans 1950-51, 42495 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Loans - old, 42496 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Maine Historical Society 1922-23, 42497 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Report of the Major Examination Committee to the Faculty May 20, 1946, 42499 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Marine Corps, 42500 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 9/9/21-12/15/21, 42501 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 1/1/22-1/30/22, 42502 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 2/1/22-3/21/22, 42503 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 4/5/22-5/31/22, 42504 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 6/7/22-6/23/22, 42505 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 8/18/22-11/27/22, 42506 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Maritime Provinces Education Report Correspondence 12/2/22-3/16/23, 42507 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Masefield - Quotation 1947, 42508 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Medical Conference (Cambridge) April 6, 1940, 42509 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Medical Insurance 1949-50, 42510 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Medical School of Maine Correspondence 1921 A - Z, 42511 (Box 9, Folder 12-29)
  - Medical School 1930-31, 42512 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Medical School 1945, 42513 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Memorial Tablet to President Hyde 1922-23, 42514 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Military - Bowdoin men in the service, 1918-1919, 42515 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Ministry (Scholarships for men preparing to enter) 1945, 42516 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Mitchell, Edward P. 1926-27, 42517 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - National Guard, 42518 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - National Security League 1920-21, 42519 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Naval Aviation, 42520 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Naval Reserve, 42521 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Regarding Oakes pictures 1944-1945, 42522 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Odiorne Correspondence 1945-46, 42523 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Passamaquoddy Project Reports Commission and Planning Board, 42524 (Volume 2)
  - Peucinian Cup Standing (First Award Feb. 1939), 42525 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Placement Bureau 1944-49, 42526 (Box 9, Folder 43-46)
  - Quoddy Project Correspondence 6/34-11/34, 42527 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Quoddy Project Correspondence 12/34-1/35, 42528 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Quoddy Project Correspondence 2/35-7/35, 42529 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Replies to New Year Greeting 1930-31, 42530 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Religious Education, Board of 1920-21, 42531 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Reports 1938, 42532 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Retirement Plan 1942, 42533 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - S.S. James Bowdoin Launching 1943, 42534 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Serbian International Educational Committee [101 Madison Ave. NYC] 1920-21, 42535 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Sesquicentennial Convocation, 42536 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Sesquicentennial certificate, Harvard University, 108288 (Ovsz-box 1)
  - Shore Property 1945, 42537 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Short Story Contest Maine Colleges 1923-24, 42538 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Smith-Towner Bill 1920-21, 42539 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Sprinklers (Wentworth) 1944-45, 42540 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - S.S. Bowdoin Victory Launching 1945, 42541 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - State Chamber of Commerce and Agricultural League Committee 1920-21, 42542 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Student Assistants, Appropriations for 1942-43, 42543 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Student Council Constitution 1949-50, 42544 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Sturtevant 1945, 42545 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Summer Camps, 42546 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Summer Session 1946 Swarthmore and Haverford, 42547 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Surplus Governmental Property, 42548 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tallman Foundation Correspondence 1930-36, 42549 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Tallman Foundation Correspondence 1937-38, 1942-44, 42550 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Tallman Professorship, 42551 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer 1949-50, 42552 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Bowdoin College Report of the Treasurer June 10, 1950, 42553 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - U.S.M.A. Student Conference on U.S. Affairs 1949, 42554 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - V-E Day Address (Letters) 1946, 42555 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Veterans Educational Facilities Program 1946-47, 42556 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
  - "Village Oracle" 1927, 42557 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Visiting Committee 1921-1924, 42558 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Visiting Committee 1922, 42559 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Visiting Committee 1925, 42560 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Visiting Committee and Finance 1925, 42561 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Minutes of Meeting of Visiting Committee 1925, 42562 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Visiting Committee Meeting April 10, 1926, 42563 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Visiting Committee 1926-42, 42564 (Box 10, Folder 26-42)
  - Visiting Committee 1942-53, 42565 (Box 11, Folder 1-20)
  - Votes 8 Copies 1923, 42566 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - State and County War Chests, 42567 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - War Credits, 42568 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Washington Conference on Education 1942, 42569 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Whittier Field Bleachers, 42570 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Philip Wilder, 42571 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - William DeWitt Hyde Launching 1943, 42572 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence 1927, 42573 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence January-March 1928, 42574 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence April 1928, 42575 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence May-June 1928, 42576 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence July 1-15, 1928, 42577 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence July 16-31, 1928, 42578 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - William Ladd Centennial -Correspondence August 1928-January 1929, 42579 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Wilson Foundation 1921-22, 42580 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - World Conference on Faith and Order - Lausanne 1927, 42581 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - World Conference on Faith and Order - 1928-1930, 42582 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - World Conference on Faith and Order 1937, 42583 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - World Conference on Faith and Order in Edinburgh, Scotland August 1937, 42584 (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
  - Yale L.L.D. 1941, 42585 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Zabriske, Rev. Alexander 1939-40, 42586 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Honorary Degrees, 1917-1952, A01.02.08.04; 42188; 2 Linear Feet
  Series contains files of correspondence between President Sills and members of the Committee on Degrees regarding nominees for and recipients of honorary degrees. Also contains personal documentation by Sills of honorary degree recipients (photos, letters, etc.). Box 2 contains statistical information regarding profession, education, etc. of degree recipients from 1919-1938.
  - President Sills Correspondence: Honorary Degrees 1917-1939, 42587 (Box 1)
  - President Sills Correspondence: Honorary Degrees 1939-1952;Summary of Honorary degrees, 1918-1946, Honorary Degrees, 1918-1946, 42588 (Box 2)
  - #290 - Honoris Causa ... 1918-1948, 42589 (Bulletin 6.2)
  - Honoris Causa ... 1949-1952, 42590 (Volume 1)
- Sesquicentennial Fund, 1947-1953, A01.02.08.05; 42189; 1.75 Linear Feet
  This series contains fund records of the Sesquicentennial Fund of Bowdoin College. Includes correspondence among Sesquicentennial Fund committee members and correspondence to those who are donating money or have donated money in the past. Also included are some solicitations and progress reports on the growth of the fund.
  - 6/5/1947 - 9/14/1948, 42591 (Box 1)
  - 9/15/1948 - 6/13/1949, 42592 (Box 2)
  - 6/14/1949 - 8/21/1950, 42593 (Box 3)
  - 8/24/1950 - 7/1/1953, 42594 (Box 4)
- Correspondence Files, 1917-1952, A01.02.08.06; 42190; 14 Linear Feet
  Correspondence is incoming and outgoing, often filed together. Filing can be by name of correspondent, by subject discussed, or by name of group involved. Activities represented include: administrative functions such as faculty affairs, curriculum issues, student academic and social affairs, communications with alumni, athletics, and external world affairs. Some correspondence parallels that found in subject files.
  Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically within each year.
  - 1917-18, C - 1921-22, W, 42595 (Box 1)
  - 1922-23, A - 1925-26, S, 42596 (Box 2)
  - 1925-26, V - 1929-30, T, 42597 (Box 3)
  - 1929-30, W - 1931-33, V, 42598 (Box 4)
  - 1931-33, W - 1935-36, S, 42599 (Box 5)
  - 1935-36, T - 1939-40, L, 42600 (Box 6)
  - 1939-40, M - 1941-42, M, 42601 (Box 7)
  - 1941-42, N - 1942-43, W, 42602 (Box 8)
  - 1943-44, A - 1943-44, W, 42603 (Box 9)
  - 1944-45, A - 1946-47, C, 42604 (Box 10)
  - 1946-47, D - 1947-48, M(1), 42605 (Box 11)
  - 1947-48, M(2) - 1948-49, T, 42606 (Box 12)
  - 1948-49, U - 1950-51, M, 42607 (Box 13)
  - 1950-51, N - 1951-52, W, 42608 (Box 14)
- Printed Ephemera, 1906-1954, undated, A01.02.08.07; 42191; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Printed ephemera includes pamphlets, programs and other printed material containing information written by or about Kenneth or Edith Sills. Also included is printed material from activities that the Sills attended or organizations of which they were members or officers. Printed ephemera continued to be collected after Sills' death and includes other material from memorial services and other programs honoring him.
  - 1906, 1909, 42609 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - October 1909-December 14, 1918, 42610 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1919-1923, 42611 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1924, 42612 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1925-1926, 42613 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1927-1928, 42614 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1929-1932, 42615 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1935-1937, 42616 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1938-1942, 42617 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1943-1948, 42618 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1949-1950, 42619 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1951-1952, 42620 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1953-1954, 42621 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Undated, 42622 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Personal - General, 1919-1969, undated, A01.02.08.08; 42192; 1.25 Linear Feet
  This series includes personal invitations, announcements, post cards, greeting cards, letters to and from Kenneth and Edith Sills as well as awards and biographical material. Invitations and announcements are mostly graduation and wedding invitations from 1932 to 1958. Letters, cards, and postcards are usually from friends or relatives, most are undated.
  - Misc. Announcements and Notifications, 42623 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Awards and Merits of K.C.M. Sills, 42624 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Biographical Material [Kenneth and Edith Sills], 42625 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Citations made in conferring honorary degrees upon K.C.M. Sills, 42626 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Passports and Misc. Documents, 42627 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - News Releases- March 1, 1919- Sept. 29,1969 and no date, 42628 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Quoddy Projects- News Clippings, 42629 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Resolutions "in memoriam", 42630 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook May 22,1943, 42631 (Volume 1)
  - Misc. Invitations- 06/15/32-04/15/35, 42632 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Invitations- 05/07/36-02/08/38, 42633 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Invitations- 03/18/39-06/29/40, 42634 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Invitations- [Wedding Invitations] 10/17/40-10/23/43, 42635 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Invitations- 11/06/43-08/31/46, 42636 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Invitations- 11/11/46-06/16/48, 42637 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Invitations- 07/10/48-06/12/50, 42638 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Invitations- 08/05/50-06/05/51, 42639 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Invitations- 06/30/51-12/04/54, 42640 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Invitations- 01/22/55-06/22/55, 42641 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Invitations- 07/08/55-10/08/55, 42642 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Invitations- 10/28/55-06/08/57, 42643 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Invitations- 06/22/57-06/17/58, 42644 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Invitations- 07/02/58-09/14/58, 42645 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letters from Sills to Mother 04/-3/1898- 08/31/1924, 42646 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Sills to Mother 12/01/24-07/03/30, 42647 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence [letters to Sills from his father] no date, 42648 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- postcards, no date, 42649 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence- cards and post cards, no date, 42650 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence- Telegrams from K.C.M.S. to Edith Sills, no date, 42651 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, no date, 42652 (Box 3, Folder 7-12)
- Academic Lecture Notes, 1901-1952, undated, A01.02.08.09; 42193; 1 Linear Feet
  Kenneth Sills' academic lecture notes are primarily notes from courses that he taught at Bowdoin in comparative literature and Latin. These notes include a set of 42 lectures, numerically arranged and a set chronologically arranged from 1935 to 1952. Much of the series is undated, but most lectures are from between 1930 and 1960. In addition, there are several folders of notes he took while he was a graduate student Harvard University. Most notes are manuscripts.
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor Lectures 1-10, 42653 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor Lectures 10-22, 42654 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor Lectures 23-51, 42655 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor Lectures 32-42, 42656 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor 1935-03/08/49, 42657 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor 04/19/50-02/25/52, 42658 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor 02/29/52-04/09/52, 42659 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Literature Lecture Notes n.d., 42660 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Literature Lecture Notes n.d., 42661 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Literature Lecture Notes n.d., 42662 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Comparative Literature Professor, 42663 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Comparative Literature Professor, 42664 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lectures Notes as Bowdoin Comparative Literature Professor, 42665 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lecture Notes as Bowdoin Literature Professor- Calendar of lecture topics and readings; hour examinations, 42666 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Notes as a Harvard Student 1901-1902, 42667 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Notes as a Harvard Student 1902-1903, 42668 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Notes as a Harvard Student, 42669 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes as a Harvard Student from class on the Renaissance, 42670 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Lecture Notes as a Bowdoin Professor Synopses of Lectures for Latin 3 September 22, 1909, 42671 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Notes as a Bowdoin Professor Latin 5 1909-1910, 42672 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Notes as a Bowdoin Professor Latin 8 Book I, 42673 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Notes as a Bowdoin Professor Latin 8 Book II, 42674 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harvard Notes, 42675 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Notes, 42676 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Notes - Historical English Grammar 1902-1903, 42677 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Harvard Notes - Later Renaissance, 42678 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Harvard University Rank List 1901-1902, 42679 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Undergraduate, 1899-1901, undated, A01.02.08.10; 42194; 0.75 Linear Feet
  This series primarily contains academic lecture notes that Sills took when he was a student at Bowdoin from 1897 to 1901. Most of the notes are undated. Also included are articles written by Sills that were printed in the Bowdoin Quill.
  - History and English Notes 1899-1901, 42680 (Box 1)
  - Government, English History, English Literature, Articles in the Bowdoin Quill, Poetry Thesis, 42681 (Box 2)
- Personal - Financial, 1906-1954, A01.02.08.11; 42195; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series includes budget item books from 1927 to 1954, and cash account books from 1906 to 1943. Sills' cash account books are lists recorded daily of items purchased and their prices. Budget items are notebooks that list Sills' private accounts of monthly expenditures, listed by categories such as insurance, groceries and entertainment. Also included is a folder of miscellaneous financial correspondence, records and receipts.
  - Cash Account Books 1906-1943, 42682 (Box 1)
  - Cash Account Books 1944-1954, Budget Items 1927-1954, and miscellaneous personal financial, 42683 (Box 2)
- Diaries, 1889-1953, A01.02.08.12; 42196; 1 Linear Feet
  Diaries are daily account books from 1891 to 1953. The books include Sills' records of travels, appointments and other daily activities and thoughts. Some diaries are more detailed than others with entries varying from several words to several pages. The series also includes his personal guest books, autograph books and book reviews.
  - Diaries 1889, 1891-1932, 42684 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 1933-1942, 42685 (Box 2)
  - Diaries 1943-1953, 42686 (Box 3)
  - Guest Books 1919-1928, Autograph Book 1889, Opera, Book Reviews [1897-1904] Latin, 42687 (Box 4)
- World War II Correspondence, 1940-1946, A01.02.08.13; 42197; 5 Linear Feet
  During World War II, President Sills and Dean Paul Nixon corresponded with Bowdoin graduates and undergraduates who were serving in the Armed Forces of the United States. This series primarily contains letters written to Sills and Nixon. Some copies of outgoing correspondence is also included.
  - Abernethy, Thomas J. (Bow 1941), 42688 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Clayton C. (Bow 1925), 42689 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, John W. (Bow 1935), 42690 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alger, F.W. (Bow 1944), 42691 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Charles W. (Bow 1934), 42692 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Frank R. (Bow 1943), 42693 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allen, Neal W., Jr. (Bow 1941), 42694 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allen, Robert H. (Bow 1946), 42695 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allen, Stanley W. (Bow 1939), 42696 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alpert, Sidney M. (Bow 1940), 42697 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Andersen, John J. (Bow 1945), 42698 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anderson, Frederick W. (Bow 1941), 42699 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Andrews, Alfred C. (Bow 1926), 42700 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Andrews, Ernest F. (Bow 1940), 42701 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armbruster, Ralph E. (Bow 1943), 42702 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arnold, Charles I. (Bow 1939), 42703 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aronson, Simeon B. (Bow 1937), 42704 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ashley, R. P. (Bow 1936), 42705 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Atkins, Elias C. (Bow 1846), 42706 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Augerson, S. (Bow 1946), 42707 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Auperin, Jean G. (Bow 1941), 42708 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Austin, Nelson D. (Bow 1941), 42709 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Avery, Myron H. (Bow 1920), 42710 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Azzarita, Manfredi (Bow 1932), 42711 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Babbitt, John A. (Bow 1943), 42712 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bachulus, John M. (Bow 1922), 42713 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bacon, Charles N. (Bow 1943), 42714 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Badger, Joseph L. (Bow 1920), 42715 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bagshaw, James H. (Bow 1944), 42716 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bailey, William I. (Bow 1945), 42717 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baker, John S. (Bow 1935), 42718 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baldwin, Harry H. III (Bow 1940), 42719 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bamforth, Leon, 42720 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Barbour, Charles M. (1933 Bow), 42721 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bargh, Samuel (Bow 1927), 42722 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Barksdale, Richard K. (Bow 1937), 42723 (Box 1, Folder 36)